<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[TunedReality]]></title><description><![CDATA[A personal blog.]]></description><link>https://vinkrish.github.io/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 17:16:46 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Recap & New Beginning]]></title><description><![CDATA[It’s been 5 yrs since I started my career in software industry. I switched jobs, started my own startup and failed in it, although I…]]></description><link>https://vinkrish.github.io//hi-folks/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://vinkrish.github.io//hi-folks/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It’s been 5 yrs since I started my career in software industry. I switched jobs, started my own startup and failed in it, although I evaluate myself from time to time it’s time to put that in writing - this also helps me plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to fear shear number of students passing out each year and then finding job while recession was still fresh in my mind. When I passed out as Elecronics and Communication Engineer I wasn’t cut out for any job in that field but programming caught my attention and decided to do Masters in Computer Science, now I feel I could have skipped college if I wanted to be where I’m today - but I wasn’t the same person back then so I don’t regret my decision. One thing I do regret is not making use of my first computer which I got at the age of 20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Success&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have come across people talking about their success stories - most of them had access to computer and resources at very young age, thinking in that direction I am happy to be where I’m today despite being late to the party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Introvert&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being an introvert has it’s downside in any industry, I’ve been working on it gradually but it’s a slow process. It does affect my career when I wasn’t voicing my opinion and bringing ideas to table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Forgetfullness or Amnesia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am fortunate to be healthy all my life and only complain I had is my forgetfulness. The best I could do is remembering my mobile number - when I learn new programming language it was never difficult to adopt and get things done but the challenge is to remember language specific consruct when I jump to learning new things.
This also doesn’t help me while having conversation about Data Structure and Algorithms which I honestly can’t remember unless I refer them again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vulnerabilities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are building cool stuff and I’m using those libraries to meet my requirements, there is always a feeling that I’m not being part of bigger open-source community where I can contribute and I’m sure it will feel nice being in that position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quest for learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I’ve tried Android App Development, Angular, React, Java back-end, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB, GraphQL, AWS. I’ve documented most of my work or demo projects on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vinkrish&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, with this blog I’m willing to go step further document my learning, be pro-active and possibly create some content for YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year again I’m learning something new - Python / Machine Learning and DevOps with Docker and Kubernetes, I’ve my doubts on how successful I can be in this challenging field but I’m willing to give my best.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title><description><![CDATA[When starting to learn new programming language - historically, it has became rudimentary to start with  “Hello World”  example, so I…]]></description><link>https://vinkrish.github.io//hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://vinkrish.github.io//hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;When starting to learn new programming language - historically, it has became rudimentary to start with &lt;strong&gt;“Hello World”&lt;/strong&gt; example, so I decided to keep this markdown file which was originally included in gatsby starter blog, but changed content to have my say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this is my first blog I thought why not try to remember all programming languages/scripts I’ve tried my hands on:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;sh&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-sh&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-sh&quot;&gt;C
C++
Java
Python
PHP
C#
Swift
JavaScript&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
I&apos;ll be sharing few things from my past experience and document everything I learn. I will also suffix programming language in title to identify content easily.</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>